<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>NoLogs VPN documentation</title>
    <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com" />
    <updated>2020-10-25T03:18:05+03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Romeo Mihalcea</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kb.nologs-vpn.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to add a new user to your VPN instance</title>
        <author>
            <name>Romeo Mihalcea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-user-to-your-vpn-instance/"/>
        <id>https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-user-to-your-vpn-instance/</id>
            <category term="wireguard"/>
            <category term="user"/>
            <category term="openvpn"/>
            <category term="console"/>

        <updated>2020-10-25T03:13:55+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/7/undraw_Add_friends_wa2a.png" alt="How to add a new user to your VPN instance" />
                    <p>In this post I will guide you through the process of adding new users to your VPN instance.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/7/undraw_Add_friends_wa2a.png" alt="How to add a new user to your VPN instance" />
                <p>In this post I will guide you through the process of adding new users to your VPN instance.</p>

<p><a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-openvpn-user/"></a><a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-openvpn-user/">How to add a new user to OpenVPN</a></p>
<p><a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-wireguard-user/">How to add a new user to Wireguard</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to add a new Wireguard user</title>
        <author>
            <name>Romeo Mihalcea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-wireguard-user/"/>
        <id>https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-wireguard-user/</id>
            <category term="wireguard"/>
            <category term="user"/>
            <category term="server"/>

        <updated>2020-10-25T03:16:02+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/6/undraw_secure_server_s9u8.png" alt="How to add a new Wireguard user" />
                    <p>In this post I will show you how to create new users for your Wireguard VPN instance.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/6/undraw_secure_server_s9u8.png" alt="How to add a new Wireguard user" />
                <p>In this post I will show you how to create new users for your Wireguard VPN instance.</p>

<p>For this operation to be possible you will need to have root access to your server. If you don't know how to gain that, please <a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-access-the-console-of-your-vm/">follow our guide</a>.</p>
<h3>Generate Wireguard client keys</h3>
<p><a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-access-the-console-of-your-vm/"></a>After logging in the ssh console you need to create the keys for the new user. Wireguard uses these keys to keep track of peers and authenticate them:</p>
<pre>docker run --rm cmulk/wireguard-docker:buster genkeys</pre>
<p>This will print 2 keys: a public and a private one:</p>
<pre>-e Private Key: 8JlkyYRuR/OdFlBOUDVfM+DknvUUsjtnduNoEeqsLWA=<br>-e Public Key: KglpBFVBdJhCIkrs8ZK/EZhkSkslz873CroBAEsg/2I=</pre>
<p>You have to copy both of them so we can go ahead with our next step (ommit the <code>-e Private Key</code> and <code>-e Public Key</code> bits).</p>
<h3>Configure the server and add the new user</h3>
<p>Now that we have our keys it is time to edit the main configuration file for Wireguardby running:</p>
<pre>nano /etc/wireguard/wg0.conf</pre>
<p>nano is a console editor and it will let you modify the file which looks something like this when being edited:</p>
<pre>[Interface]<br>Address = 192.168.20.1/24<br>SaveConfig = true<br>PostUp = iptables -A FORWARD -i wg0 -j ACCEPT; iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o eth0 -j MASQUERADE<br>PostDown = iptables -D FORWARD -i wg0 -j ACCEPT; iptables -t nat -D POSTROUTING -o eth0 -j MASQUERADE<br>ListenPort = 5555<br>PrivateKey = 6IrKiXy2jdMxu9MQwh5Tl+EqxltMWPQvPv9at5YOrlQ=<br><br>[Peer]<br>PublicKey = hgx2jsPIsp6E2cltv1BIgf+YHQVBuazsvt6XuceHTXk=<br>AllowedIPs = 192.168.20.2/32</pre>
<p>We can see there are 2 sections here:</p>
<ol>
<li>Interface</li>
<li>Peer</li>
</ol>
<p>The Interface part is about the server and the Peer is actually the first client that is allowed to connect. You can see that the first peer has a <code>PublicKey</code> (like the one you just generated) and an <code>AllowedIPs</code> param. We will need to replicate that and create a new <code>Peer</code> so the new config will look like this:</p>
<pre>[Interface]<br>Address = 192.168.20.1/24<br>SaveConfig = true<br>PostUp = iptables -A FORWARD -i wg0 -j ACCEPT; iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o eth0 -j MASQUERADE<br>PostDown = iptables -D FORWARD -i wg0 -j ACCEPT; iptables -t nat -D POSTROUTING -o eth0 -j MASQUERADE<br>ListenPort = 5555<br>PrivateKey = 6IrKiXy2jdMxu9MQwh5Tl+EqxltMWPQvPv9at5YOrlQ=<br><br>[Peer]<br>PublicKey = hgx2jsPIsp6E2cltv1BIgf+YHQVBuazsvt6XuceHTXk=<br>AllowedIPs = 192.168.20.2/32<br><br>[Peer]<br>PublicKey = KglpBFVBdJhCIkrs8ZK/EZhkSkslz873CroBAEsg/2I=<br>AllowedIPs = 192.168.20.3/32</pre>
<p>Look carefully and take note that I added a new <code>Peer</code> with the public key we just generated above and I also incremented the <code>AllowedIPs</code> from <code>192.168.20.2/32</code> to <code>192.168.20.3/32</code> to avoid any IP space collisions.</p>
<p>You can save the file by pressing <code>CTRL+X</code> and writing the letter <code>y</code> once prompted to save the changes.</p>
<p>Following this change you need to restart the Wireguard instance:</p>
<pre>docker restart $(docker ps -aq)</pre>
<h3>Create the client config file</h3>
<p>There's one more step and that is to create the new client config that the new member should use to connect. For this let's create a copy of the original client.config file and edit the Interface part. The Peer, in this case, is the server so that section needs to stay the same:</p>
<pre class="aLF-aPX-K0-aPE">[Interface]
Address = 192.168.20.3/24
PrivateKey = 8JlkyYRuR/OdFlBOUDVfM+DknvUUsjtnduNoEeqsLWA=
ListenPort = 0 

[Peer]
PublicKey = g4gaGC/F2Fz3E2cH7Ek1ZQTRTEHosZQ4oEOzpf6e/y0=
Endpoint = 165.227.147.194:58281
AllowedIPs = 0.0.0.0/0,::/0 #makes sure ALL traffic routed through VPN
PersistentKeepalive = 25</pre>
<p>What I edited here is the Interface <code>Address</code> to the one we allocated to our new user (<code>192.168.20.3</code>) and the <code>PrivateKey</code> which I updated with the private key that we generated above: <code>8JlkyYRuR/OdFlBOUDVfM+DknvUUsjtnduNoEeqsLWA=</code> . Other than that pretty much remained the same.</p>
<p>That's it! I know it is a bit difficult and we're working on automating this process in the future.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to add a new OpenVPN user</title>
        <author>
            <name>Romeo Mihalcea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-openvpn-user/"/>
        <id>https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-add-a-new-openvpn-user/</id>
            <category term="user"/>
            <category term="server"/>
            <category term="openvpn"/>

        <updated>2020-10-25T03:16:06+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/5/undraw_server_cluster_jwwq.png" alt="" />
                    <p>In this post we will show you how to create new users for your OpenVPN instance.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/5/undraw_server_cluster_jwwq.png" alt="" />
                <p>In this post we will show you how to create new users for your OpenVPN instance.</p>

<p>For this operation to be possible you will need to have root access to your server. If you don't know how to gain that, please <a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-access-the-console-of-your-vm/">follow our guide</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-access-the-console-of-your-vm/"></a>After logging in the ssh console you can run the following command in order to create new users:</p>
<pre>docker run -v $OVPN_DATA:/etc/openvpn --log-driver=none --rm -it kylemanna/openvpn easyrsa build-client-full CLIENTNAME nopass</pre>
<p>Replace <code>CLIENTNAME</code> with a username.</p>
<p>This will generate the files for the new user and place them in the right directory. The command will also prompt for your password (<strong>it's the one that was emailed to you when we sent you the first config</strong>).</p>
<p>With the new user created we need to retrieve the config so here's a new command you need to run:</p>
<pre>docker run -v $OVPN_DATA:/etc/openvpn --log-driver=none --rm kylemanna/openvpn ovpn_getclient CLIENTNAME &gt; CLIENTNAME.ovpn</pre>
<p>The above command printed the entire config and piped it into a file called <code>CLIENTNAME.ovpn</code> which is now sitting in your home folder. To view and copy the contents you can run <code>cat CLIENTNAME.ovpn</code>. That's it!</p>
<p>In all these commands you need to replace <code>CLIENTNAME</code> with the username.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to access the console of your VM</title>
        <author>
            <name>Romeo Mihalcea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-access-the-console-of-your-vm/"/>
        <id>https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-access-the-console-of-your-vm/</id>
            <category term="server"/>
            <category term="root"/>
            <category term="console"/>

        <updated>2020-10-25T03:18:05+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/4/undraw_server_cluster_jwwq.png" alt="How to access the console of your VM" />
                     In this post I will show you how to reset your server's root password and gain access to the root console. The next thing&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/4/undraw_server_cluster_jwwq.png" alt="How to access the console of your VM" />
                
  <p>
    In this post I will show you how to reset your server's root password and gain access to the root console.
  </p>

  <p>
    The next thing after receiving your config should be to allow others to connect without sharing the security credentials but, by doing so, you will have to work with the unix console a bit and that means gaining access to the root user.
  </p>

  <p>
    After install, our drone/worker removes the authentication key that was used to create the VM. This means that, without a root password, you will not be able to login to the ssh. Luckily, we can reset that password and login so go ahead to the&nbsp; VM page and navigate to <b>Access</b> part.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/4/screenshot-cloud.digitalocean.com-2020.10.25-02_05_47.png" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" srcset="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/4/responsive/screenshot-cloud.digitalocean.com-2020.10.25-02_05_47-xs.png 300w ,https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/4/responsive/screenshot-cloud.digitalocean.com-2020.10.25-02_05_47-sm.png 480w ,https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/4/responsive/screenshot-cloud.digitalocean.com-2020.10.25-02_05_47-md.png 749w"  height="744" width="1242" alt="" />
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    From the screenshot you can see the "Reset Root Password" button. Click on it and wait for an email to arrive with the new password but bear in mind that your VM has to be powered off for this operation to continue.
  </p>

  <p>
    With the new root password in your clipboard go ahead and SSH into your server.&nbsp; This is a bit tricky because the ssh password authentication is not enabled so you will need to use the console access from the same Access page.
  </p>

  <p>
    You will be prompted for the password and also for a new one immediately after logging in.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to upgrade your server</title>
        <author>
            <name>Romeo Mihalcea</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-upgrade-your-server/"/>
        <id>https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/how-to-upgrade-your-server/</id>
            <category term="upgrade"/>
            <category term="server"/>

        <updated>2020-10-25T01:53:17+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/undraw_upgrade_06a0.png" alt="How to upgrade your server" />
                     Upgrading your server is easy and it shouldn't take more than a couple of minutes. In this article I will show you how to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/undraw_upgrade_06a0.png" alt="How to upgrade your server" />
                
  <p>
    Upgrading your server is easy and it shouldn't take more than a couple of minutes. In this article I will show you how to do it, step by step.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Our deploy worker only creates the cheapest plan when spawning your server to save on your expenses and because a single client should be handled pretty well by the server anyway.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Once you start adding more clients and your workload is putting a higher pressure on the server it is time to log into your Digitalocean account and perform the upgrade which involves a server reboot so be prepared for a drop on the connection with the VPN.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    The first step is to identify your server and click on it so we can navigate to the info page where all the options will be available to us. One thing that I recommend before any major operation such as this one is to take a snapshot of your server. Keep in mind that, during the creation of the snapshot, your VM instance will be powered down.<br>
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/snapshot-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" srcset="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/responsive/snapshot-2-xs.png 300w ,https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/responsive/snapshot-2-sm.png 480w ,https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/responsive/snapshot-2-md.png 749w"  height="806" width="1128" alt="" />
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    This operation will allow us to revert back to a working state in case something unplanned takes place.
  </p>

  <p>
    Now that our server has a snapshot we can go ahead with the upgrade process so let's navigate to the "Resize" page.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/resize-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" srcset="https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/responsive/resize-2-xs.png 300w ,https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/responsive/resize-2-sm.png 480w ,https://kb.nologs-vpn.com/media/posts/2/responsive/resize-2-md.png 749w"  height="1147" width="1104" alt="" />
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    Usually, a VPN server is heavier on the CPU&nbsp; than anything else so I recommend looking at upgrades in terms of CPU more than anything else. Keep in mind that your VM needs to be powered off before attempting the upgrade.
  </p>

  <p>
    That's it. Once the upgrade process is done you can power the VM back on and connect to your VPN.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
